<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on The Hungry Wonderer</title>
    <link>/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on The Hungry Wonderer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-06-03-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-06-03-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>A new blog&amp;hellip;again Given that most of my posts are now quite programming centric, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move away from the world of CMS (Wordpress) and into the a slightly more streamlined approached of using markdown files with R, RStudio and R Markdown.
Why move?  I recently discovered a number of R bloggers using websites powered by Jekyll and Github.com and am hoping that the workflow will be better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Politicians Poisoned Politics - FT article</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-04-20-how-politicians-poisoned-politics-ft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-04-20-how-politicians-poisoned-politics-ft/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, there was a pretty interesting article in the Financial Times on the somewhat liberal use of statistics by politicians.
Here are some highlights that I thought were worth capturing:
Frankfurt concluded that the difference between the liar and the bullshitter was that the liar cared about the truth — cared so much that he wanted to obscure it — while the bullshitter did not. The bullshitter, said Frankfurt, was indifferent to whether the statements he uttered were true or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Forest Watch</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-10-11-global-forest-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-10-11-global-forest-watch/</guid>
      <description>Came across this website today called Global Forest Watch. It’s got some really great mapping visuals. Having dabbled in a bit of mapping in R, the graphics that this site has is really, really amazing.
I tried simple zooming in on Malaysia, Indonesia and Singapore and was quite surprised to see a fair bit of tree cover gain, about 9.7 million hectares to be exact. Sadly, the amount of loss was almost twice that at about 18.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>