<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on The Hungry Wonderer</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on The Hungry Wonderer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Variable Importance with Random Forests</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-10-04-on-variable-importance-with-rf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-10-04-on-variable-importance-with-rf/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionOne of the big challenges in predictive modelling is determining which variables to use as predictors. This challenge becomes particularly difficult when the number of possible predictors becomes very large, making manual exploratory methods or the more “traditional” forward/backward stepwise regression models impractical, particularly when interactions between variables need to be considered.
One very practical and useful by-product of the random forest algorithm (and gradient boosting machines) is the variable importance which can be calculated as part of the model fitting process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R distribution prefixes - in plain English</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-05-23-r-distribution-prefixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-05-23-r-distribution-prefixes/</guid>
      <description>In R, probability distributions are prefixed by four different letters, namely d, p, q and r. I’ve always found the help pages on these fairly hard to understand mainly because the terminology used is not what I’ve been taught–nothing wrong with that, just makes things a bit confusing.
If you’re familiar with PDF’s and CDF’s, then here’s the mapping from R help to more common language.
PrefixR help descriptorMy interpretationddensityProbability Density Function (PDF)pdistribution functionCumulative Distribution Function (CDF)qquantile functionInverse CDFrgenerate random deviatesDraw random samples from the specified distributionA really good reference for this is found here: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>